<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>critical reflections on a rope fastened between</title>
    <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/critical-reflections/</link>
    <description>Recent content in critical reflections on a rope fastened between</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021-2022 Urmila Nair</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/critical-reflections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The &#34;Secret&#34; in Translation---On the limits of anthropological awareness</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/secret-in-translation-lacito-abstract/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/secret-in-translation-lacito-abstract/</guid>
      <description>This is the abstract&amp;mdash;in French and English&amp;mdash;of a research paper I presented at the CNRS research unit LaCiTO&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Jeux de Langage&lt;/em&gt; seminar on April 19th, 2022. The article draws on linguistic anthropology, semiotics, Tibetan studies, and translation theory to discuss the translation of an esoteric Tibetan Buddhist ritual, the Nechung &lt;em&gt;kang-so&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Benjamin On Translation _In_ Translation, Part IV</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partiv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partiv/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critical reading, through a semiotic lens, of Walter Benjamin&amp;rsquo;s essay on &amp;lsquo;The Translator&amp;rsquo;s Task.&amp;rsquo; Together with it, I present critical comparative notes on the three translations referenced, viz. Harry Zohn’s 1968 English, Steven Rendall’s 2000 English, and Maurice de Gandillac’s 2000 French translations. I derive from these critical comparisons &lt;strong&gt;a set of rules of good academic translation practice&lt;/strong&gt;, which is presented at the end. This is the last of four installments of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Benjamin On Translation _In_ Translation, Part III</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partiii/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Feb 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partiii/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critical reading, through a semiotic lens, of Walter Benjamin&amp;rsquo;s essay on &amp;lsquo;The Translator&amp;rsquo;s Task.&amp;rsquo; Together with it, I present critical comparative notes on the three translations referenced, viz. Harry Zohn’s 1968 English, Steven Rendall’s 2000 English, and Maurice de Gandillac’s 2000 French translations. I derive from these critical comparisons &lt;strong&gt;a set of rules of good academic translation practice&lt;/strong&gt;, which is presented at the end. This is the third of four installments of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Benjamin On Translation _In_ Translation, Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partii/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-partii/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critical reading, through a semiotic lens, of Walter Benjamin&amp;rsquo;s essay on &amp;lsquo;The Translator&amp;rsquo;s Task.&amp;rsquo; Together with it, I present critical comparative notes on the three translations referenced, viz. Harry Zohn’s 1968 English, Steven Rendall’s 2000 English, and Maurice de Gandillac’s 2000 French translations. I derive from these critical comparisons &lt;strong&gt;a set of rules of good academic translation practice&lt;/strong&gt;, which is presented at the end. This is the second of four installments of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Benjamin On Translation _In_ Translation, Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-parti/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/walter-benjamin-translators-task-critical-reading-parti/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critical reading, through a semiotic lens, of Walter Benjamin&amp;rsquo;s essay on &amp;lsquo;The Translator&amp;rsquo;s Task.&amp;rsquo; Together with it, I present critical comparative notes on the three translations referenced, viz. Harry Zohn’s 1968 English, Steven Rendall’s 2000 English, and Maurice de Gandillac’s 2000 French translations. I derive from these critical comparisons &lt;strong&gt;a set of rules of good academic translation practice&lt;/strong&gt;, which is presented at the end. This is the first of four installments of this article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Translation thesis submitted at ESIT:&lt;br /&gt;_La Littérature Orale en Bretagne_ (Oral literature in Brittany)&lt;br /&gt;(Reposted)</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/my-esit-masters-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Nov 2021 07:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/my-esit-masters-thesis/</guid>
      <description>This is the master&amp;rsquo;s thesis (&lt;em&gt;mémoire&lt;/em&gt;) that I submitted at ESIT (&lt;em&gt;École supérieure d&amp;rsquo;interprètes et de traducteurs&lt;/em&gt;) in June, 2021, towards a master&amp;rsquo;s in editorial, technical and financial translation. The thesis was selected for publication on the open archive HAL-DUMAS. It was written under the direction of Mme Marie-Paule Chamayou, with Mary-Ann Constantine as my translation reader and Hanna Martikainen as jury member. It was awarded a &amp;ldquo;mention excellente&amp;rdquo; (highest honors) with a grade of 19/20.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Cartesian Counterpublic:&lt;br /&gt;a review of François Héran&#39;s book&lt;br /&gt;_Lettre aux professeurs sur la liberté d&#39;expression_</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/heran-book-review-freedom-of-expression/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/heran-book-review-freedom-of-expression/</guid>
      <description>This is a book review of sociologist François Héran&amp;rsquo;s 2021 &lt;em&gt;Lettre aux professeurs sur la liberté d&amp;rsquo;expression&lt;/em&gt;. Analyzing the current French conjuncture, marked indelibly by gruesome violence and frenzied polemics surrounding the caricatures of the Prophet Muhammad, Héran exhorts teachers&amp;mdash;and citizens more generally&amp;mdash;to work to preserve democracy. Héran proposes the judicious exercise of freedom of expression in public discourse: public critique, he stresses, must be founded in reason, valid information and respect for all beliefs. Héran&amp;rsquo;s work yields the following insight: his addressees constitute what one might term a &lt;em&gt;Cartesian counterpublic&lt;/em&gt;, with all the fraught implications the term carries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on André Jolles&#39;s *Simple Forms* – Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/andre-jolles-simple-forms-partii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/andre-jolles-simple-forms-partii/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of a critical review of 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;-century literary critic and art historian André Jolles&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Simple Forms&lt;/em&gt; and his attempt at theorizing &amp;ldquo;the totality of all literary art&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Une critique traductologique&amp;nbsp;: pourquoi la théorie interprétative du sens ne peut expliquer la question de style, Partie II*</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/strategies-de-traduction-partii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/strategies-de-traduction-partii/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critique of the interpretive theory of meaning (&lt;em&gt;la théorie interprétative du sens&lt;/em&gt;) proposed by French translation theorists Danica Seleskovitch and Marianne Lederer. This is the second part of my critique, and is excerpted from a thesis on translation that I wrote at ESIT in early 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflections on André Jolles&#39;s *Simple Forms* – Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/andre-jolles-simple-forms-parti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/andre-jolles-simple-forms-parti/</guid>
      <description>This is a critical review of 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;-century literary critic and art historian André Jolles&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Simple Forms&lt;/em&gt; and his attempt at theorizing &amp;ldquo;the totality of all literary art&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>*Une critique traductologique : pourquoi la théorie interprétative du sens ne peut expliquer la question de style, Partie I*</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/strategies-de-traduction-parti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/strategies-de-traduction-parti/</guid>
      <description>I present here a critique of the famous interpretive theory of meaning (&lt;em&gt;la théorie interprétative du sens&lt;/em&gt;) proposed by French translation theorists Danica Seleskovitch and Marianne Lederer. This critique is excerpted from a thesis on translation that I wrote at ESIT in early 2021.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
