<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>translations on a rope fastened between</title>
    <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/translations/</link>
    <description>Recent content in translations on a rope fastened between</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© 2021 Urmila Nair</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/translations/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Subtitled Video: an interview with Claire Voisin, mathematician</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/subtitled-video-an-interview-with-claire-voisin-mathematician/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 May 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/subtitled-video-an-interview-with-claire-voisin-mathematician/</guid>
      <description>I subtitled this video of an interview with renowned French mathematician Claire Voisin. In it she reflects on how she came to study mathematics, on its boundless nature, on the inadequacies of math teaching in schools, and on the experience of doing mathematics. What fascinates me is the way mathematicians often seem to anthropomorphize their own mathematical thought processes. Ramanujan famously attributed his mathematical insights to a goddess. Voisin here speaks of an &amp;ldquo;ideal person&amp;rdquo; inside herself who seems to do mathematics even as she performs banal chores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A letter to history and geography teachers, or How to reflect freely on freedom of expression, Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/a-letter-to-history-and-geography-teachers-or-how-to-reflect-freely-on-freedom-of-expression-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Apr 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/a-letter-to-history-and-geography-teachers-or-how-to-reflect-freely-on-freedom-of-expression-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an article on freedom of expression (Fr. &lt;em&gt;liberté d&amp;rsquo;expression&lt;/em&gt;) by sociologist and demographer François Héran. Composed as an address to history and geography teachers in France in the wake of the murder of Samuel Paty, the article was published on October 30, 2020 in &lt;em&gt;La Vie des Idées&lt;/em&gt;, the online journal of the &lt;em&gt;Institut du Monde contemporain&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Collège de France&lt;/em&gt;. This is the second part of my translation of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A letter to history and geography teachers, or How to reflect freely on freedom of expression, Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/a-letter-to-history-and-geography-teachers-or-how-to-reflect-freely-on-freedom-of-expression-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/a-letter-to-history-and-geography-teachers-or-how-to-reflect-freely-on-freedom-of-expression-part-i/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an article on freedom of expression (Fr. &lt;em&gt;liberté d&amp;rsquo;expression&lt;/em&gt;) by sociologist and demographer François Héran. Composed as an address to history and geography teachers in France in the wake of the murder of Samuel Paty, the article was published on October 30, 2020 in &lt;em&gt;La Vie des Idées&lt;/em&gt;, the online journal of the &lt;em&gt;Institut du Monde contemporain&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Collège de France&lt;/em&gt;. This is the first part of my translation of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The murder of Samuel Paty and the dangers of a France divided against itself, Part II</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-murder-of-samuel-paty-and-the-dangers-of-a-france-divided-against-itself-part-ii/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-murder-of-samuel-paty-and-the-dangers-of-a-france-divided-against-itself-part-ii/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an interview given by French philosopher and sociologist Edgar Morin to the newspaper &lt;em&gt;Le Monde&lt;/em&gt; in November 2020. In the interview, Morin analyzes the latest ideological fractures that rend France. This is the second part of my translation of the interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subtitled Video Excerpt: a talk by sociologist François Héran on freedom of expression&lt;br /&gt; (with **_Translation Notes_**)</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/subtitled-video-excerpt-a-talk-by-sociologist-fran%C3%A7ois-h%C3%A9ran-on-freedom-of-expressionbr-/-with-_translation-notes_/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/subtitled-video-excerpt-a-talk-by-sociologist-fran%C3%A7ois-h%C3%A9ran-on-freedom-of-expressionbr-/-with-_translation-notes_/</guid>
      <description>This video that I have subtitled in English is excerpted from a talk in French by François Héran, sociologist and demographer. It focuses on the idea of freedom of expression (Fr. &lt;em&gt;liberté d&amp;rsquo;expression&lt;/em&gt;). The talk was addressed to history and geography teachers in France in the wake of the murder of Samuel Paty. Himself a history and geography teacher, Paty had used caricatures of the Prophet Muhammad in his class and was consequently killed by a young jihadist of Chechen origin. Héran gave this talk on October 30, 2020 during his course on migration at the &lt;em&gt;Collège de France&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Innovation, Employment, Inequality, Part I&lt;br /&gt;(with **_Translation Notes_**)</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/innovation-employment-inequality-part-ibr-/with-_translation-notes_/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Mar 2021 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/innovation-employment-inequality-part-ibr-/with-_translation-notes_/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an economics article published in &lt;em&gt;La Vie des Idées&lt;/em&gt;, the online journal of the &lt;em&gt;Institut du Monde contemporain&lt;/em&gt; of the &lt;em&gt;Collège de France&lt;/em&gt;. The journal publishes essays, articles and book reviews by academics from various disciplines. This is the first part of my translation of this article. It is presented with &lt;strong&gt;translation notes&lt;/strong&gt;, aimed at showing the reader some of the supporting structure, normally invisible, of a translation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The murder of Samuel Paty and the dangers of a France divided against itself, Part I</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-murder-of-samuel-paty-and-the-dangers-of-a-france-divided-against-itself-part-i/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-murder-of-samuel-paty-and-the-dangers-of-a-france-divided-against-itself-part-i/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an interview given by French philosopher and sociologist Edgar Morin to the newspaper &lt;em&gt;Le Monde&lt;/em&gt; in November 2020. In the interview, Morin analyzes the latest ideological fractures that rend France. This is the first part of my translation of the interview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The *gwerz* of Louis Le Ravallec</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-gwerz-of-louis-le-ravallec/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/the-gwerz-of-louis-le-ravallec/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of ethnologue Donatien Laurent&amp;rsquo;s seminal study of the &lt;em&gt;gwerz&lt;/em&gt; of Louis Le Ravallec. A &lt;em&gt;gwerz&lt;/em&gt; is a ballad form belonging to the oral traditions of Britanny. Laurent&amp;rsquo;s article was published in 1967 in the journal &lt;em&gt;Arts et traditions populaires&lt;/em&gt;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracks and Traces of Mont Blanc’s Itineraries: an Approach Through Wayfaring</title>
      <link>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/tracks-and-traces-of-mont-blancs-itineraries-an-approach-through-wayfaring/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.aropefastenedbetween.fr/tracks-and-traces-of-mont-blancs-itineraries-an-approach-through-wayfaring/</guid>
      <description>This is my translation of an article by French geographer Pierre de Potestad. The article traces the history of itinerancy and itineraries along the slopes of Mont Blanc. The article and translation were published in 2021 in the online journal &lt;em&gt;Révue de géographie alpine&lt;/em&gt;, the Journal of Alpine Research.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
